<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>https://conoroneill.net/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://conoroneill.net/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangle.js and Open Source pointing to the future of health platforms and wearables</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2019/11/25/bangle-js-open-source-pointing-to-future-of-health-platforms-and-wearables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2019/11/25/bangle-js-open-source-pointing-to-future-of-health-platforms-and-wearables/</guid>
      <description>First things first, Gordon Williams&amp;rsquo;s KickStarter for Bangle.js finishes in three days. If you have interest in any of: sustainable Open Source, JavaScript, Machine Learning, wearables, Open APIs, health, hacking or IOT, you should back it. Heck even if you want to see what Chinese manufacturers are able to cram into an inexpensive device in 2019, you should get one.
Second - how did I manage to wait exactly one year between blogposts?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A decade since my first Android phone - The HTC G1</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/11/25/a-decade-since-my-first-android-phone-the-htc-g1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 17:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/11/25/a-decade-since-my-first-android-phone-the-htc-g1/</guid>
      <description>Ten years ago today, I received my first Android phone, an HTC G1, from a US eBay seller.
Here it is, still working! It&amp;rsquo;s sitting on an Amazon Fire HD (stunningly good value) beside a Huawei Honor Play (a stand-in for my broken Galaxy S8+ and a fantastic phone at a crazy low price).
It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine now, but back then, Android was nowhere. The G1 was the first Android device and many thought it compared very badly to the equivalent iPhone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating RSS feeds for Cork&#39;s Evening Echo newspaper website with Node.js and Serverless</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/09/08/creating-rss-feeds-for-corks-evening-echo-newspaper-website-with-node.js-and-serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 09:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/09/08/creating-rss-feeds-for-corks-evening-echo-newspaper-website-with-node.js-and-serverless/</guid>
      <description>For nearly 10 years I relied on Twitter as my primary source of news. Now that I have left Twitter and Facebook mostly behind, I have turned back to email newsletters and RSS for non-tech news. I never stopped using RSS for tech news.
Of course, in that time, many news sites have forgotten about RSS. e.g. The Cork Evening Echo in Ireland has some pages that refer to RSS but they are no longer functional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Big Thank You to Ben Heck</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/09/07/a-big-thank-you-to-ben-heck/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 07:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/09/07/a-big-thank-you-to-ben-heck/</guid>
      <description>Ben Heckendorn recently ended his YouTube show with Element14 after several years of wonderful maker videos. Whilst the channel continues with a new name and other presenters, Ben has moved on.
I had a hiatus from electronics for 20 years after I left UCD Elec Eng in 1992. In 2012 I discovered the world of Arduino and quite soon after, the Raspberry Pi launched. I&amp;rsquo;ve had so much fun building stupid (and every so often, not stupid) things over the past 6 years and I think Ben had a lot to do with that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I may be totally done with Twitter-style sites including Mastodon</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/08/30/i-may-be-totally-done-with-twitter-style-sites-including-mastodon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 12:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/08/30/i-may-be-totally-done-with-twitter-style-sites-including-mastodon/</guid>
      <description>I gave up on Twitter in Nov 2017 due to their complete inaction around
online abuse, particularly that of women. I setup a Mastodon account at
that time and didn&amp;rsquo;t use it much initially but ramped up activity recently.
Despite all the articles written recently about how Mastodon is the nice
anti-Twitter, the sad reality is that asshole behaviour has nothing to do
with the tech or the tools, it has to do with people being assholes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>email-to-hugo - Update your Hugo blog via email</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/08/15/email-to-hugo-update-your-hugo-blog-via-email/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 09:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/08/15/email-to-hugo-update-your-hugo-blog-via-email/</guid>
      <description>My most productive period of blogging here was when I used the late lamented Posterous. That was due to its blogging-by-email feature. Whilst a similar feature is available for hosted blogs like WordPress, things are a lot more difficult if you have a static blog. That Posterous blog (e.g. this one) was converted to several other systems over the years and is currently generated by Hugo. My workflow for blogging is generally to write a new markdown file, add it to the git repo, commit it along with any images and then wait until CircleCI re-generates the blog output and deploys it to S3/Cloudfront.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First few minutes with the RasPad</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/08/13/first-few-minutes-with-the-raspad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 14:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/08/13/first-few-minutes-with-the-raspad/</guid>
      <description>My RasPad arrived this morning and I&amp;rsquo;m very impressed after just a few minutes of checking it out.
I grabbed a Pi3 that has RetroPie installed on it and inserted it into the bay.
Loved playing SNES Galaxians at lunchtime!
Update October 13th 2018 - Dead RasPad For a few weeks the RasPad was awesome. I had a Pi3+ installed and a wireless keyboard. I even used it for proper hands-on Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First live test of my new email-to-hugo blogging tool</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/08/12/first-live-test-of-my-new-email-to-hugo-blogging-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 16:51:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/08/12/first-live-test-of-my-new-email-to-hugo-blogging-tool/</guid>
      <description>I have almost completed a simple new tool which enables you to send blog
content via email. The emails are converted to Markdown files and then
uploaded to my Hugo source repo, along with any inline images.
CircleCI then automatically rebuilds and redeploys my blog to S3.
I&amp;rsquo;ll post full details and source code over the next few days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fund this project to add Allwinner VPU support to the official Linux kernel</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/03/17/fund-allwinner-vpu-support-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 09:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/03/17/fund-allwinner-vpu-support-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>Anyone who has any interaction with technology benefits from all of the work done by Open Source developers around the world from the past few decades. Unfortunately there are far more takers than givers. I think there is a strong chance that many OSS developers will become burnt out and disenchanted with building things for free when others reap the commercial rewards.
Many of the Chinese silicon and box companies are particularly bad at providing proper maintanined OS support for their devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running new C code on a 1982 ZX Spectrum in 2018</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/02/13/running-c-code-on-a-1982-zx-spectrum-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/02/13/running-c-code-on-a-1982-zx-spectrum-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>The 1980s home computer retro scene remains very vibrant. I dip a toe in every so often and recently have been enjoying the new Speccy games that I&amp;rsquo;ve found on Indie Retro News.
One thing that caught my eye with these releases was the mentions of &amp;ldquo;engines&amp;rdquo;. It turns out that people have been building games engines for the ZX Spectrum for years. Mostly in C it seems and mostly using the z88dk toolchain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you think of when you read that Open Source is 20 years old?</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/02/04/what-do-you-think-of-when-you-read-open-source-is-20-years-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/02/04/what-do-you-think-of-when-you-read-open-source-is-20-years-old/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I read that Open Source is offically 20 years old. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean free software or GNU or anything like that, just the definition and initiative itself. It made me think about all of open source (lower case) and free software that&amp;rsquo;s had an impact on me since I was a teenager. Here&amp;rsquo;s that as a quick brain-dump. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ve missed tons and will update as they pop into my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading YouTube videos  on Android for offline viewing later</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/02/02/downloading-youtube-videos-for-offline-viewing-on-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/02/02/downloading-youtube-videos-for-offline-viewing-on-android/</guid>
      <description>One of the all-time great tools of the internet era is youtube-dl. It enables you to download any YouTube video for watching offline/later. It has been a fantastic boon over the years for watching all my hundreds of subscribed channels when in planes, trains, automobiles and treadmills. It&amp;rsquo;s also the basis for my own YTPodders tool for generating podcasts from videos.
Normally I run it on the PC and copy the files to the mobile devices, tablets or media players.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I may have over-blinged my NodeConf EU badge</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/01/01/i-may-have-over-blinged-my-nodeconf-eu-badge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/01/01/i-may-have-over-blinged-my-nodeconf-eu-badge/</guid>
      <description>If you attended NodeConf EU 2017 in Kilkenny, Ireland, you&amp;rsquo;ll know all about the digital badge powered by Espruino that we created with Gordon Williams. You can read more about it on the nearForm blog and check out the docs site.
I hope you&amp;rsquo;ve continued to learn about Espruino and the power of JavaScript on tiny microcontrollers. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget it&amp;rsquo;s entirely Open Source Software and Hardware. Our Github repo is here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Media Players in 2017</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2017/12/29/my-media-players-in-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2017/12/29/my-media-players-in-2017/</guid>
      <description>Our journey with media players started a long time ago by adding a hardware hack to an original pre-360 XBOX so it could run XBMC. We&amp;rsquo;ve gone through a bunch of devices since, with the Raspberry Pi being the mainstay since 2012, until its lack of x265, 4K and Netflix meant we had to look elsewhere in 2017.
Quick side-note: By complete coincidence, XMBC has just been released today on the XBOX One.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solved - Missing synced contacts on new iPhone 8</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2017/12/28/solved-missing-synced-contacts-on-iphone-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2017/12/28/solved-missing-synced-contacts-on-iphone-8/</guid>
      <description>The parents both got new iPhone 8&amp;rsquo;s for Christmas. I figured it&amp;rsquo;d take 10 minutes to tranfer them from a 5s and a 6 respectively. Boy was I wrong.
Five hours later I finally had them both working ok. Hopefully this post will save you some of my pain with these magical seamless awesome incredible devices (as Tim likes to call them).
 Builtin transfer process - Make sure you have Bluetooth on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End of an era - Our Wii is going in the attic</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2017/12/24/end-of-an-era-our-wii-is-going-in-the-attic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2017/12/24/end-of-an-era-our-wii-is-going-in-the-attic/</guid>
      <description>Last night I setup a monitor in the 12yo&amp;rsquo;s room for his Android media box and his Nintendo Switch. He told me not to bother setting up the Wii. And I was kinda sad.
We became a Nintendo house in 2005 with my US purchase of the original DS for the 6yo. This September he started college. In that time we have bought DS Lites, DSis and 3DSes. And some of them are still in intermittent use from the 18yo down to the 11yo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Puck.js with the KuLight RGB Bluetooth Lightbulb</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2017/08/20/using-puck-js-with-kulight-rgb-bluetooth-lightbulb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 18:11:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2017/08/20/using-puck-js-with-kulight-rgb-bluetooth-lightbulb/</guid>
      <description>I have a massive backlog of tech posts to do but I never quite finish the projects to the level I want and they are left hanging. So I&amp;rsquo;m going to start posting more WIP stuff from now on and hopefully they&amp;rsquo;ll be useful to someone.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been a long-time fan of the Espruino project created by Gordon Willams and have had great fun with the original board, the Pico and Puck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All the grisly details of Skeletony and the Halloween Doorbell of Doooooom V2.0</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2016/11/29/all-the-grisly-details-of-skeletony-and-the-halloween-doorbell-of-doom-v20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 20:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2016/11/29/all-the-grisly-details-of-skeletony-and-the-halloween-doorbell-of-doom-v20/</guid>
      <description>Intro After the silly complexity and Hackaday article! of last year, I decided to keep it simple for Halloween this year. Of course that worked out :-)
The kids&amp;rsquo; favourite thing from all our Halloweens was the doorbell that made scary sounds. So that became the focus. As I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really done anything with my two C.H.I.P.s, I picked one to handle the bulk of the activity. I immediately became a big fan of its small size, built-in Wifi and simple Linux UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick review of the BLU Life Mark £80 Android phone</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2016/10/02/quick-review-of-the-blu-life-mark-android-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 17:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2016/10/02/quick-review-of-the-blu-life-mark-android-phone/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago, I took my Galaxy S6 out for a run in the rain and it died. Based on previous experience with the horror known as Vodafone Ireland Insurance, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d be looking at 10 days minimum to get a replacement. This proved 100% accurate as the usual completely inept software that connects Vodafone&amp;rsquo;s PDP-11 to Stay Mobile&amp;rsquo;s Commodore 64 had cancelled my insurance without notification several months previously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing YTPodders - Get your fave YouTubers as audio podcasts on your phone</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2016/05/02/introducing-ytpodders-get-your-fave-youtubers-as-audio-podcasts-on-your-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 19:32:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2016/05/02/introducing-ytpodders-get-your-fave-youtubers-as-audio-podcasts-on-your-phone/</guid>
      <description>Like my kids, I love regular YouTubers. My particular favourites are the tech, craft, metal and woodworking people who make amazing things every week. Those gals and guys have to be watched to really get the value from them and here&amp;rsquo;s a few more worth looking at too, of course not forgetting these other gems.
But there are others I love equally where it&amp;rsquo;s mostly about what they are saying. For example, Ethan Newberry (aka The Ginger Runner) does a fantastic weekly live session where he mostly interviews Ultra runners.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>