<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>https://conoroneill.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 10:00:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://conoroneill.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A quick thought on failed computers in education</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2021/09/19/a-quick-thought-on-failed-computers-in-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 10:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2021/09/19/a-quick-thought-on-failed-computers-in-education/</guid>
      <description>I saw two related threads over the past few days about computers in education.
One called the Rasperry Pi a failure as it didn&amp;rsquo;t achieve its original mission.
Clickbait title time: The Raspberry Pi failed (a thread).
The original mission statement of the Pi was to be a modern BBC computer - a cheap educational resource that could be scattered throughout schools for kids to learn on.
By that lofty aim, it&amp;#39;s failed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TikTok RSS Flat - Generate RSS feeds from TikTok using GitHub OCTO Flat Data</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2021/07/15/tiktok-rss-feeds-using-github-octo-flat-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 05:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2021/07/15/tiktok-rss-feeds-using-github-octo-flat-data/</guid>
      <description>Gen-X nerds continue to ruin the internet for Gen-Z by implementing RSS feeds for TikTok 😁
I was really intrigued by the launch of GitHub OCTO Flat Data, having already been a longtime fan of Simon Willison&amp;rsquo;s work (all the way back to the early days of Django). There is something very powerful in there that is not obvious on first look. Connecting it to Low-Code platforms could unleash lots of crazy fabulous new ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pano2Insta - Panoramic photo to Instagram converter</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2021/07/12/pano2insta-panoramic-photo-to-instagram-converter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 05:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2021/07/12/pano2insta-panoramic-photo-to-instagram-converter/</guid>
      <description>My Huawei P30 Pro takes great panoramic photos but Instagram isn&amp;rsquo;t able to use them properly. The trick is to split them into multiple 1080x1080 photos (up to 10 of them) and include all of them in one post. People can then swipe right and left to get a pseudo-panoramic view.
There are lots of ad-supported or pay-for apps to do this in the Google Play Store. But I figured it was hardly difficult to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preserving old blogs/sites and the importance of GitHub</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2021/01/17/preserving-old-sites-importance-of-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 17:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2021/01/17/preserving-old-sites-importance-of-github/</guid>
      <description>Many of us remember the cultural ignorance of Yahoo deleting GeoCities and Twitter deleting Posterous off the web. Those responsible are no better than library arsonists.
Whether you think all of that published creativity was rubbish or amazing, there is something very wrong with it all just disappearing. The Internet Archive does an amazing job but it&amp;rsquo;s simply impossible for it to keep up.
So I&amp;rsquo;ve taken it as a bit of a challenge to try and keep as much old content as possible online if I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering Citizen Non-Developers</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2020/12/10/empowering-citizen-non-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 07:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2020/12/10/empowering-citizen-non-developers/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about tools for non-developers for several years. It seems to me that all the big players are leaving behind this important group. They keep talking about citizen developers, low-code and no-code. But the focus is on &amp;ldquo;code&amp;rdquo;, so most of the world will self-select out of using any of those tools, including the no-code ones. Even the title of Satya Nadella&amp;rsquo;s article this week is &amp;ldquo;Want a More Equitable Future?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting PCManFM on your Raspberry Pi to remember SMB/Samba passwords</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2020/12/08/pcmanfm-raspberry-pi-smb-samba-password/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 07:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2020/12/08/pcmanfm-raspberry-pi-smb-samba-password/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s always this time of year when I say I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely blog more next year. I was also sure I&amp;rsquo;d blog tons during lockdown but I was busy doing other things.
This is the type of post I used to do very regularly on this blog so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d ease myself back in with a simple one.
If you access Samba/SMB shares on your home network via the stock PCManFM file manager on your Raspberry Pi, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably have hit the problem that it forgets the password on reboot, even tho you ticked &amp;ldquo;remember forever&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why running TensorFlow Lite Micro on very inexpensive devices changes everything</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2019/12/04/why-running-tensorflow-lite-for-microcontrollers-on-extremely-inexpensive-devices-changes-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2019/12/04/why-running-tensorflow-lite-for-microcontrollers-on-extremely-inexpensive-devices-changes-everything/</guid>
      <description>When NearForm Research announced Bangle.js at NodeConf EU with Gordon Williams from Espruino, we highlighted the uniqueness of having an inexpensive off-the-shelf Chinese smartwatch running both JavaScript and Google&amp;rsquo;s TensorFlow Lite for Microcontrollers.
Whilst hardcore technology people got the implications of this, most people didn&amp;rsquo;t. You can now run Machine Learning models directly on the $5 chip inside a watch and do all of the interaction inside a web browser. If you can&amp;rsquo;t wait until Bangle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Wasmer on a Raspberry Pi 4 with 64-bit userland</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2019/12/02/running-wasmer-on-a-raspberry-pi-4-with-64bit-userland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2019/12/02/running-wasmer-on-a-raspberry-pi-4-with-64bit-userland/</guid>
      <description>Like many people I&amp;rsquo;m excited by all of the possibilities opened up with WebAssembly/WASM. Most recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been keeping an eye on Wasmer and similar projects that enable WASM outside of the browser.
So when I saw that you can now run it on a Raspberry Pi, I had to give it a try. But it&amp;rsquo;s not quite as straightforward as the article suggests and this is what I had to do to get it working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangle.js and Open Source pointing to the future of health platforms and wearables</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2019/11/25/bangle-js-open-source-pointing-to-future-of-health-platforms-and-wearables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2019/11/25/bangle-js-open-source-pointing-to-future-of-health-platforms-and-wearables/</guid>
      <description>First things first, Gordon Williams&amp;rsquo;s KickStarter for Bangle.js finishes in three days. If you have interest in any of: sustainable Open Source, JavaScript, Machine Learning, wearables, Open APIs, health, hacking or IOT, you should back it. Heck even if you want to see what Chinese manufacturers are able to cram into an inexpensive device in 2019, you should get one.
Second - how did I manage to wait exactly one year between blogposts?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A decade since my first Android phone - The HTC G1</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/11/25/a-decade-since-my-first-android-phone-the-htc-g1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 17:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/11/25/a-decade-since-my-first-android-phone-the-htc-g1/</guid>
      <description>Ten years ago today, I received my first Android phone, an HTC G1, from a US eBay seller.
Here it is, still working! It&amp;rsquo;s sitting on an Amazon Fire HD (stunningly good value) beside a Huawei Honor Play (a stand-in for my broken Galaxy S8+ and a fantastic phone at a crazy low price).
It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine now, but back then, Android was nowhere. The G1 was the first Android device and many thought it compared very badly to the equivalent iPhone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating RSS feeds for Cork&#39;s Evening Echo newspaper website with Node.js and Serverless</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/09/08/creating-rss-feeds-for-corks-evening-echo-newspaper-website-with-node.js-and-serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 09:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/09/08/creating-rss-feeds-for-corks-evening-echo-newspaper-website-with-node.js-and-serverless/</guid>
      <description>For nearly 10 years I relied on Twitter as my primary source of news. Now that I have left Twitter and Facebook mostly behind, I have turned back to email newsletters and RSS for non-tech news. I never stopped using RSS for tech news.
Of course, in that time, many news sites have forgotten about RSS. e.g. The Cork Evening Echo in Ireland has some pages that refer to RSS but they are no longer functional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Big Thank You to Ben Heck</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/09/07/a-big-thank-you-to-ben-heck/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 07:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/09/07/a-big-thank-you-to-ben-heck/</guid>
      <description>Ben Heckendorn recently ended his YouTube show with Element14 after several years of wonderful maker videos. Whilst the channel continues with a new name and other presenters, Ben has moved on.
I had a hiatus from electronics for 20 years after I left UCD Elec Eng in 1992. In 2012 I discovered the world of Arduino and quite soon after, the Raspberry Pi launched. I&amp;rsquo;ve had so much fun building stupid (and every so often, not stupid) things over the past 6 years and I think Ben had a lot to do with that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I may be totally done with Twitter-style sites including Mastodon</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/08/30/i-may-be-totally-done-with-twitter-style-sites-including-mastodon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 12:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/08/30/i-may-be-totally-done-with-twitter-style-sites-including-mastodon/</guid>
      <description>I gave up on Twitter in Nov 2017 due to their complete inaction around
online abuse, particularly that of women. I setup a Mastodon account at
that time and didn&amp;rsquo;t use it much initially but ramped up activity recently.
Despite all the articles written recently about how Mastodon is the nice
anti-Twitter, the sad reality is that asshole behaviour has nothing to do
with the tech or the tools, it has to do with people being assholes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>email-to-hugo - Update your Hugo blog via email</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/08/15/email-to-hugo-update-your-hugo-blog-via-email/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 09:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/08/15/email-to-hugo-update-your-hugo-blog-via-email/</guid>
      <description>My most productive period of blogging here was when I used the late lamented Posterous. That was due to its blogging-by-email feature. Whilst a similar feature is available for hosted blogs like WordPress, things are a lot more difficult if you have a static blog. That Posterous blog (e.g. this one) was converted to several other systems over the years and is currently generated by Hugo. My workflow for blogging is generally to write a new markdown file, add it to the git repo, commit it along with any images and then wait until CircleCI re-generates the blog output and deploys it to S3/Cloudfront.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First few minutes with the RasPad</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/08/13/first-few-minutes-with-the-raspad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 14:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/08/13/first-few-minutes-with-the-raspad/</guid>
      <description>My RasPad arrived this morning and I&amp;rsquo;m very impressed after just a few minutes of checking it out.
I grabbed a Pi3 that has RetroPie installed on it and inserted it into the bay.
Loved playing SNES Galaxians at lunchtime!
Update October 13th 2018 - Dead RasPad For a few weeks the RasPad was awesome. I had a Pi3+ installed and a wireless keyboard. I even used it for proper hands-on Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First live test of my new email-to-hugo blogging tool</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/08/12/first-live-test-of-my-new-email-to-hugo-blogging-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 16:51:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/08/12/first-live-test-of-my-new-email-to-hugo-blogging-tool/</guid>
      <description>I have almost completed a simple new tool which enables you to send blog
content via email. The emails are converted to Markdown files and then
uploaded to my Hugo source repo, along with any inline images.
CircleCI then automatically rebuilds and redeploys my blog to S3.
I&amp;rsquo;ll post full details and source code over the next few days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fund this project to add Allwinner VPU support to the official Linux kernel</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/03/17/fund-allwinner-vpu-support-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 09:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/03/17/fund-allwinner-vpu-support-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>Anyone who has any interaction with technology benefits from all of the work done by Open Source developers around the world from the past few decades. Unfortunately there are far more takers than givers. I think there is a strong chance that many OSS developers will become burnt out and disenchanted with building things for free when others reap the commercial rewards.
Many of the Chinese silicon and box companies are particularly bad at providing proper maintanined OS support for their devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running new C code on a 1982 ZX Spectrum in 2018</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/02/13/running-c-code-on-a-1982-zx-spectrum-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/02/13/running-c-code-on-a-1982-zx-spectrum-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>The 1980s home computer retro scene remains very vibrant. I dip a toe in every so often and recently have been enjoying the new Speccy games that I&amp;rsquo;ve found on Indie Retro News.
One thing that caught my eye with these releases was the mentions of &amp;ldquo;engines&amp;rdquo;. It turns out that people have been building games engines for the ZX Spectrum for years. Mostly in C it seems and mostly using the z88dk toolchain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you think of when you read that Open Source is 20 years old?</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/02/04/what-do-you-think-of-when-you-read-open-source-is-20-years-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/02/04/what-do-you-think-of-when-you-read-open-source-is-20-years-old/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I read that Open Source is offically 20 years old. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean free software or GNU or anything like that, just the definition and initiative itself. It made me think about all of open source (lower case) and free software that&amp;rsquo;s had an impact on me since I was a teenager. Here&amp;rsquo;s that as a quick brain-dump. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ve missed tons and will update as they pop into my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading YouTube videos  on Android for offline viewing later</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.net/2018/02/02/downloading-youtube-videos-for-offline-viewing-on-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.net/2018/02/02/downloading-youtube-videos-for-offline-viewing-on-android/</guid>
      <description>One of the all-time great tools of the internet era is youtube-dl. It enables you to download any YouTube video for watching offline/later. It has been a fantastic boon over the years for watching all my hundreds of subscribed channels when in planes, trains, automobiles and treadmills. It&amp;rsquo;s also the basis for my own YTPodders tool for generating podcasts from videos.
Normally I run it on the PC and copy the files to the mobile devices, tablets or media players.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
